C. Carlo Fazioli

625 H St NE Apt 708
Washington D.C.

→ +1(626)298-1212

□ carlo@carlofazioli.com

□ carlofazioli.com

□ carlofazioli

⊕ carlofazioli

I am a research scientist and software engineering generalist with experience in cloud computing and artificial intelligence. I am a lifelong learner confident in my ability to rapidly cultivate new knowledge, as well as drill down into concept details.

Current Position

2018 - Present **Software Engineer**, *Group W, Inc.*, Vienna VA.

Main contributor on a 2021 Military Operations Research Society Barchi prize winning, multi-year, multi-million dollar DARPA contract to develop an AI wargaming application. Project responsibilities include:

- Architecting microservices with Kubernetes/Docker on a private 11-node 1,240 CPU cluster, as well as a full installation on Microsoft Azure
- Designing AI algorithms with NNs, MCTS, and RL
- O Developing application source code with python, bash, Django, and GNU Make
- Constructing an application API to support front end Vue developers
- Managing GitLab issues, branches, merges, releases, and testing/deployment pipelines for a team of 6 developers
- o Administrating MongoDB from the mongo shell, and with pymongo

General corporate responsibilities include:

- Reviewing academic research literature
- Managing interns

- Contributing to contract proposal BD
- Briefing industry stakeholders

Education

2005 – 2009 **Ph.D. Mathematics**, *University of Illinois at Chicago*, Chicago IL.

2000 – 2004 B.S. Mathematics, University of San Francisco, San Francisco CA.

Previous Positions

2016 – 2018 **Econometric Modeler**, *International Monetary Fund*, Washington DC.

Collaborated with IMF economists on economic model development; researched, designed, and implemented algorithms for use by IMF staff; pursued exploratory research into technology solutions for IMF institutional needs; addressed technical needs of individual IMF staff.

2013 – 2016 **Assistant Teaching Professor**, *Dept. of Mathematics*, Drexel University, Philadelphia,

Developed course and lab materials; lectured, graded exams, monitored students' use of online resources, assigned final grades; assisted students as needed outside of class or in office hours; directed teaching assistants.

2011 – 2013 **Postdoctoral Research Associate**, *Dept. of Mathematical Sciences*, New Jersey Inst. of Tech., Newark, NJ.

Researched, designed, and coded novel algorithms for use in fluid dynamics simulations; briefed research supervisor; presented findings to collaborators and conference attendees.

Hobbies and Interests

- \circ Solving the NYT crossword puzzle daily $\ \circ$ Science fiction lit/TV/movies
- Running, cycling, and yoga
- Cloud computing

- Advent of Code and CTFs
- Bug bountying and cybersecurity